<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Michelle Holiman -</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/travel-tips/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:06:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What Clothes to Pack for Your Norway Trip</title>
		<link>/blog/what-to-pack-for-your-norway-trip/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 18:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Norway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Packing List]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Want to know what clothes to pack for your Norway trip? In this straight-forward post, I'll tell you what to pack and what to leave behind.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/what-to-pack-for-your-norway-trip/">What Clothes to Pack for Your Norway Trip</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Michelle Holiman</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-5-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-153" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-5-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-5-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-5-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-5.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p style="font-size:18px"><em><strong>Affiliate Disclosure: This blog post contains affiliate links, which means I may earn a commission if you make a purchase through some of these links. There is no additional cost to you, and I only recommend products and services that I genuinely believe will add value, especially when you are choosing what to pack for your Norway trip. Thank you for supporting my blog!</strong></em></p>



<p>What even are people wearing to Norway? I remember checking the weather for my trip in May to find sub-freezing lows, but highs of 65℉ (18.3℃.) One thing is for sure, Norway has got range. This large difference in temperatures opens the door for a lot of questions. What should I wear hiking? Will it be warm enough to swim? How much should I pack to keep warm? I have learned that poor planning can really ruin a trip, and with that in mind, I felt I should make a blog post dedicated to what to pack for your Norway trip! After tons of research, and then personally testing out items, I found a few things I was so grateful to have, and some things that never made it out of the suitcase. There is even a lil packing checklist I made just for you at the bottom of the page. Let&#8217;s dive into exactly what to pack for your Norway Trip!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Suit Up</h3>



<p>Preparing for the elements might vary from breezy T-shirts to<a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-cord-fjord-down-coat/26881.html?dwvar_26881_color=PNGR"> puffy jackets</a> &#8211; all within the same day. The best decision? Layering. I know it is cliché, but taking off layers when you are hot or insulating when you are cold can make a tough hike significantly more comfortable, especially when you get hot during the uphill, but cold at the top. Here is what to look into so you can have the best experience</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>My number 1 favorite thing &#8211; seriously, I cannot give it enough hype &#8211; <a href="https://amzn.to/4czlQTl">Merino Wool Baselayers</a></strong></h4>



<p>Did anyone else have the experience as a child of getting thermal underwear and it being itchy, uncomfortable, and WAY too hot? Imagine all of those problems floating away <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f60c.png" alt="😌" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f54a.png" alt="🕊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> If that sounds good to you, you will LOVE Merino wool base layers. They breathe, wick sweat, don’t smell, keep you at a perfect temperature, and are so freaking comfortable. I am convinced that it is because of magic that these work so well. If there is any article of clothing whose praises I will sing from the mountain tops, it is these.</p>



<p>The only downside is that they can be a little pricey, but they do go on sale quite often. I bought the top and bottoms at the end of winter for between $60-$70 each. If you aren’t in a rush, wait for a good sale! <a href="https://amzn.to/3Z0UD8K">Here is another well-reviewed pair</a> that is a little less expensive if you want options. Not to be dramatic, but they might just change your life &#8211; or at least change the way you hike in cold weather. This is for sure one item you should pack for your Norway trip.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Mid-Layers</strong></h4>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-medium is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="240" height="300" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-2-240x300.jpg" alt="Michelle in heavy duty winter gear in Svalbard" class="wp-image-155" style="width:359px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-2-240x300.jpg 240w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-2-819x1024.jpg 819w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-2-768x960.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-2.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></figure></div>


<p>For your mid layers, you will want something with minimal bulk so wearing an outer layer will still be comfortable and non-constricting. I used some of my long-sleeved tops from home, as well as some <a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-r1-fleece-pullover/40119.html?dwvar_40119_color=BLK&amp;cgid=womens-fleece-pullovers">lightweight pullovers</a>. You can also get a <a href="https://amzn.to/4dCGRxJ">fleece vest</a> if you are going further north where temperatures are extra cold. One thing to remember here is where you can layer up. For the coldest days, I had my base layer, a pair of jeans, and a pair of <a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-quandary-hiking-pants-regular/55417.html?dwvar_55417_color=FGE&amp;cgid=womens-pants-jeans">looser hiking pants</a> over the top of those. Adding in a pair of gloves and a hat (both of which I forgot and bought in Norway) is a lifesaver. The other amazing thing I was so grateful I had was a nice, warm scarf. Especially in the Svalbard portion of my trip, the chill wind was especially hard on my nose and cheeks. It was so helpful to have a scarf that I could loop around and cover my face. I seriously considered bringing a <a href="https://amzn.to/46UgYXK">balaclava,</a>  but I ended up leaving it at home. I would 100% recommend one if you venture far north and earlier in the year than I did. A <a href="https://amzn.to/4duVmDS">thick pair of wo</a><a href="https://www.rei.com/product/165398/rei-co-op-merino-wool-lightweight-hiking-crew-socks">ol socks </a>paired with my hiking boots were incredibly nice to have as well.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Outer layers</strong></h4>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-2-683x1024.jpg" alt="Cameron in a heavy winter coat" class="wp-image-160" style="width:359px;height:auto" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-2-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-2-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-2-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-2.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure></div>


<p>A few things to consider when choosing an outer coat are warmth potential and wind &amp; rainproofing abilities. Let&#8217;s talk about both of these <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f447-1f3fb.png" alt="👇🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Warmth Potential</strong></h5>



<p>When I started researching, everywhere I looked talked about how Down is the very best insulator out there. It tends to be:<br>1.) More breathable than synthetic-filled jackets, which is a huge plus for hiking.<br>2.) Lightweight, less bulky, and more compressible which is important when you have to prioritize every inch of space in your travel bags<br>3.) Fairly Durable. While water can compress the fluffiness (known as loft,) down jackets are, overall, pretty long-lasting and considered a good investment.</p>



<p>Now, if you spend any time looking at down jackets, you will come across the term “Fill Power” with an associated number. Usually, the number is between 500 and 800 and is simply a unit of measure for the quality of down used which directly impacts how warm the jacket will be. Generally* the lower the number, the less insulating; the higher, the more insulating. For context, I used a down jacket with 600 Fill Power and it did the trick for me, especially when paired with underlayers.</p>



<p>*<em>Some coats can weigh more with a lower-rated fill power and are still warm simply because the coat is stuffed with more down. Be sure to compare the coat&#8217;s weight and the fill power if you are particular about your insulation</em>.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Wind &amp; Rain Proofing</strong></h5>



<p>The other thing to know about down jackets is that the feathers do not do well if they get wet. They will pack down, cling together, and fail to insulate you effectively. If you plan on being in a wet climate, be sure to use a <a href="https://amzn.to/3ArHiw3">waterproof outer layer</a> or pop a <a href="https://amzn.to/3WViLak">raincoat</a> on over your down jacket. I cannot emphasize enough the power of a good rain jacket. Seriously, it rains a lot in Norway and it was a lifesaver for me to quickly put one on while it was pouring. If you are layering a raincoat over your heavy jacket, you may want to go up a size when you purchase.</p>



<p>The time of year I visited was May, and I did not pack an intense outer layer for my legs such as snowboarding pants or a snowsuit. This was partially because I didn’t have enough space, and I only own a lightweight pair. With my base layer, long socks, jeans, and hiking pants over the top, I didn’t ever get miserably cold. In places like Svalbard, certain tours supply you with warm-weather gear. If you want to book a tour, keep an eye out for this detail.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-4-1024x683.jpg" alt="Michelle in hiking clothes in the lofoten Islands of Norway" class="wp-image-157" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-4-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-4-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-4-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-4.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>I didn&#8217;t even think about that!</strong></h3>



<p>When you choose what to pack for your Norway trip, some things are obvious &#8211; socks, underwear, etc &#8211; so I won&#8217;t waste your time reminding you to bring them. However, some things make a huge difference in your trip that might take you by surprise. Here are a few of mine:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3Xcwnzb">Dark Eye Mask</a>. If you go to Norway during the summer, you will experience extended hours of daylight and Midnight Sun. Having an eye mask can make a huge difference in your quality of sleep!</li>



<li>Swimsuit. In the land of snow and mountains? Yes! The number of beautiful lakes and fjords available to swim in is substantial. The water will probably be cold, but it is absolutely refreshing. Additionally, a sauna is a true Scandinavian experience, but some may require a swimsuit.</li>



<li><a href="https://amzn.to/4dTvmSo">Sunglasses</a>. Trust me on this one, especially if you plan on hiking in snow. On a bright day, the snow was so reflective that I found myself squinting. One of our tour guides mentioned that she gets headaches if she doesn&#8217;t wear sunglasses and is out hiking all day. I didn&#8217;t have to test this one out thankfully.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What to skip</strong></h3>



<p><em>Hey Michelle, what about the fancy stuff? </em>I am so glad you asked! From time to time, I have packed a really elegant outfit for photos at the top of a mountain. I can safely say that this didn&#8217;t happen during this trip. I think this is partially because getting to the top of a mountain in Norway requires Maximum Effort<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> and I wanted to keep my hiking backpack as dialed in as possible. While I love the idea of a photo like that, it wasn&#8217;t one of my goals for this trip (though I do admire anyone who accomplishes this feat.) In this same line of thought, there weren&#8217;t many places that had an upscale dress code. Much of the activities in Norway &#8211; at least, the ones that drew me in &#8211; are outdoorsy. If I had to choose between packing a pretty dress or making sure I had space for a puffer coat, I would choose the coat. That isn&#8217;t to say you can&#8217;t pack something nice! If you plan your trip well, and around the activities you enjoy, you should be able to pack whatever outfits support that desire.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-683x1024.jpg" alt="Person in a raincoat with an umbrella walking the streets of Bergen, Norway" class="wp-image-154" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Packing-list-1.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>Choosing what to pack for your Norway trip shouldn&#8217;t be a stressful thing. Keep the goal of staying warm, dry, and comfortable at the forefront of your mind and you will be totally fine! Whether you are walking the colorful streets of Bergen, or hiking the peaks of Svalbard, the right attire can enhance your experience. Especially in Norway, the experience is everything! If you want a free packing list to get the creative juices flowing, tap the link below. Happy traveling!</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-content-justification-center is-layout-flex wp-container-core-buttons-is-layout-1 wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button has-custom-width wp-block-button__width-75"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-background wp-element-button" href="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-Packing-List.pdf" style="background-color:#55c9ec">Norway Packing List</a></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/what-to-pack-for-your-norway-trip/">What Clothes to Pack for Your Norway Trip</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Michelle Holiman</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Complete 2-Week Itinerary from my EPIC trip to Norway</title>
		<link>/blog/norway-adventure-itinerary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michelle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Norway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Itineraries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nas.local/wordpress/?p=73</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>An all-encompassing, honest itinerary of my 2-week adventure in Norway.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/norway-adventure-itinerary/">My Complete 2-Week Itinerary from my EPIC trip to Norway</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Michelle Holiman</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-103" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-953-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>


<p></p>



<p>Hey all! I had a lot of people asking for my specific itinerary from my trip to Norway. Knowing what I like when reading an itinerary, I made it short, sweet, and with minimal side notes. This is also the honest version of where I went and what I did &#8211; both the exciting and the &#8220;change-of-plans&#8221; experiences. When inclement weather or closures happened, I wanted to incorporate what I would have done or other suggestions for you to help plan your trip. There are also helpful links to hotels, companies, or businesses that I visited while there. If you have any questions, feel free to leave a comment or shoot me a DM on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/michellecholiman/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/michellecholiman/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Instagram</a>!</p>



<p>Enjoy! </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-116" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-77-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Famous view of Bryggen, the centuries-old wooden buildings on the wharf</figcaption></figure></div>


<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Spot #1 Bergen</strong> <strong>and the Fjords</strong></p>



<p><strong>Day one</strong></p>



<p>Arrived at Bryggen at 1 pm and dropped off luggage</p>



<p>Walked to the famous fish market (got some delicious fish soup and fish and chips) and explored the market</p>



<p>Explored the shops and alleys at Bryggen</p>



<p>Walked to the side around of the harbor facing Bryggen, got some photos</p>



<p>Explored the surrounding streets, enjoying the art and architecture&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fought sleep, but began losing. Headed back to<a href="https://www.airbnb.com/slink/IFbHjh1I" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.airbnb.com/slink/IFbHjh1I" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Airbnb</a></p>



<p>In bed at 7:40 pm</p>



<p><strong>Day 2 &#8211; explored the town</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-768x1151.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-313-scaled.jpg 1708w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The streets of Bergen are so beautiful in the springtime</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Slept in <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f44f-1f3fb.png" alt="👏🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f44f-1f3fb.png" alt="👏🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f44f-1f3fb.png" alt="👏🏻" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p>Had breakfast at Gødt Brød (Good Bread)</p>



<p>Explored and learned some history at <a href="https://bymuseet.no/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://bymuseet.no/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rosenkrantz Tower and Håkon´s Hall</a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Went to a free art gallery (it was so-so) called KRAFT&nbsp;</p>



<p>Checked out more shops and art stores/galleries at Bryggen&nbsp;</p>



<p>Visited Byparken and took pictures of the flowers, statues, and National Theatre, then checked out the neighboring shops</p>



<p>After dinner (of kebab <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f60b.png" alt="😋" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />) went by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nostressbergen?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/nostressbergen?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">No Stress</a> for drinks and to play Mario Kart (unfortunately the chord in the N64 was not working, so we hung out and chatted.)</p>



<p>Watched the sunset around Bryggen (absolutely beautiful)</p>



<p><strong>Day 3 Norway in a Nutshell <a href="https://www.fjordtours.com/en/norway/tours" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.fjordtours.com/en/norway/tours" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">(book tour here)</a></strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-111" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-364-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Seeing a fjord by boat is nothing short of spectacular</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Hopped on the Bergen Train at 7, enjoyed the views</p>



<p>Hopped on the famous Flåm Railway</p>



<p>Had 1:30 to explore Flåm, bought some Scandinavian Sweaters and ate lunch, loaded the bus for Stegastein Viewpoint&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:30-minute tour to Stegastein Viewpoint <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f929.png" alt="🤩" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p>Got back, did a 1-hour hike at the Nature Trail &#8211; ate a delicious cinnamon custard Bolle</p>



<p>Get in line for the boat 15 minutes early (note where the captain is facing and grab a spot by the rail facing the same direction. </p>



<p>Fjord cruise of Nærøyfjord (a branch of Songefjord)</p>



<p>Bus back (stopping at the panoramic hotel along the way)</p>



<p>Tacos and a lil ice cream after dinner at the wharf</p>



<p>Picked up muffins from the 7/11 for a to-go breakfast for tomorrow&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Day 4</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-114" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-768x1151.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-125-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Quaint little cities fill the valleys and make for amazing photos!</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Catch the early bus to Norheimsund, and get out at Steinsdalsfossen to have the whole waterfall to yourself (before the tour busses come in!)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Walk 35-45 minutes to Norheimsund (taking in the beautiful scenery along the way)</p>



<p>Stop for coffee and a view at Kaffe Kap</p>



<p>Stroll to the <a href="https://www.hardangerfjord-adventure.no/%C3%B8ystese-tours?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwk8e1BhALEiwAc8MHiFURoduJyRVLJuUjbNz8piPx-aic6gLDdwMOp1Nos3gRCp_QLjqlgBoCaUsQAvD_BwE" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.hardangerfjord-adventure.no/%C3%B8ystese-tours?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwk8e1BhALEiwAc8MHiFURoduJyRVLJuUjbNz8piPx-aic6gLDdwMOp1Nos3gRCp_QLjqlgBoCaUsQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hardanger Fjord Adventure</a> &#8211; 1:15 minute high-speed Fjord Safari</p>



<p>Catch the bus back to Bergen</p>



<p>Hit up the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://sjofartsmuseum.museumvest.no/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sjofartsmuseum.museumvest.no/" target="_blank">Maritime Museum</a> before they close (I wanted to learn about the Viking history of the area, this was a great option, but it also showcases the history of boats and Norwegian Seafaring)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enjoy a loop around the large lake at Fyllingsdalen and climb through the trees to find the rocky outcrop over the lake</p>



<p>Pop back to Bryggen for a classic Beer Garden experience, enjoying the sunny outdoors (food available as well)</p>



<p>Go to bed because exhaustion has hit pretty hard</p>



<p><strong>Day 5&nbsp;</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-101" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-396-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Be prepared for a little scrambling on this hike</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Wake up early and grab breakfast at the bottom of Mount Fløy (Floybannen Funicular)</p>



<p>Ride the Funicular up to the top</p>



<p>Visit the goats to the right of the funicular exit first, then start the Vidden hike</p>



<p>Hike and hike and hike for about 6 hours (don’t forget Kvikk hiking chocolate! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f36b.png" alt="🍫" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />)</p>



<p>Eat a late lunch at the <a href="https://ulriken643.no/kafe" data-type="URL" data-id="https://ulriken643.no/kafe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ulriken Cafe</a></p>



<p>Take the Ulriken Cable Car down and catch the bus to <a href="https://www.citysauna.no/en" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.citysauna.no/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">City Sauna</a></p>



<p>2 Hour Sauna cruise (for two <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f495.png" alt="💕" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />)</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>melt in the sauna</li>



<li>Cold plunge in the fjord&nbsp;</li>



<li>Drink LOTS of water</li>



<li>Vibe with your music&nbsp;</li>



<li>Pick a favorite essential oil to add to the sauna water</li>
</ul>



<p>Feel AMAZING after</p>



<p>Dinner at Olivia (pizza and focaccia were so good)</p>



<p>Pack up and go to bed</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Spot #2 Longyearbyen, Svalbard</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-106" style="object-fit:cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-768x1151.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-729-scaled.jpg 1708w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">We asked our tour guide if we could stop at one of these signs!</figcaption></figure></div>


<p><strong>Day 6&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Haul everything to the station and catch the flight to Longyearbyen (Svalbard)</p>



<p>Beer tasting at the <a href="https://svalbardbrewery.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://svalbardbrewery.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Svalbard Bryggri</a></p>



<p>Dinner at Svalbar&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Day 7</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-109" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-508-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Walruses are a new favorite animal of mine</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Walrus safari with <a href="https://www.bettermoments.no/our-trips/walrus-safari-two-tons-of-happiness/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.bettermoments.no/our-trips/walrus-safari-two-tons-of-happiness/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Better Moments</a> tour company (lunch on the boat)</p>



<p>Dinner at Nuga Sushi&nbsp;</p>



<p>Guided evening hike to the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.snowfoxtravel.com/activities" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.snowfoxtravel.com/activities" target="_blank">Global Seed Vault with Snow Fox</a> and then to the top of Blomsterdalshøgda for great cardio exercise and even better views </p>



<p>Watch the Midnight sun from the beach&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go to bed INCREDIBLY tired</p>



<p><strong>Day 8</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-107" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-768x1151.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-640-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">View from the top of Blomsterdalshøgda</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Guided nature hike into Bjordallen with Snow Fox (see Arctic foxes, Svalbard Reindeer, and a plethora of wild birds.)(lunch on the hike)</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://svalbardmuseum.no/en" data-type="URL" data-id="https://svalbardmuseum.no/en" target="_blank">Svalbard Museum</a> (to learn the rich history of the area) (we had to choose between this and the <a href="https://visitsvalbard.travelize24.com/clientfiles/svalbardbooking.asp?WebSiteUser=none&amp;productcode=g3visit&amp;lang=uk&amp;pk_vid=dfe8d90c31ce93c9172296536021d3d1" data-type="URL" data-id="https://visitsvalbard.travelize24.com/clientfiles/svalbardbooking.asp?WebSiteUser=none&amp;productcode=g3visit&amp;lang=uk&amp;pk_vid=dfe8d90c31ce93c9172296536021d3d1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">coal mine tour</a> and ultimately chose this option, but you could easily swap out this choice if you wanted to see Mine Number 3)</p>



<p>Dinner at Saenphet Thai in the shopping center (really pretty views of the street from the main window)</p>



<p><strong>Day 9</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-104" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-873-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The iconic Rorbus of Hamnøy</figcaption></figure>



<p>Pack up and check out of hotel&nbsp;</p>



<p>Walk the city shops and pick up souvenirs&nbsp;</p>



<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/cafehuskies?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/cafehuskies?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Husky Cafe</a> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f60d.png" alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> pet the pups and drink some tea&nbsp;</p>



<p>Catch the bus to the airport</p>



<p class="has-small-font-size"><strong><em>Quick Tour Company Notes:</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-small-font-size"><em>If you want to go outside of the city limits, there is a very real possibility of running into a polar bear (there are signs at a few points outside of town warning you of this.) Because of that, it is not wise to leave town without a guide, or unprepared to scare off a polar bear (most of the time this is done with a flare gun, but all locals carry guns for worst-case scenario situations.) Tours are what 99.99% of visitors do to explore outside of Longyearbyen. I loved both of the companies listed above, they were by far some of the best tours I have ever been on as far as quality of information, structure of the tour, and genuine friendliness and character of our guides &#8211; some of which I am now friends with on Instagram.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p class="has-small-font-size"><em>It should be stated that the odds of seeing a Polar Bear are INCREDIBLY low, but there is a long history of people being hurt or killed by bears since the discovery of Svalbard &#8211; one incident happening as recently as 2022. Going with a guide is the best way to explore and stay safe.</em></p>



<p>Land in Lofoten, pick up car and drive to <a href="https://rorbuer.no/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rorbuer.no/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eliassen Rorbuer in Hamnøy</a></p>



<p>Watch the sunset</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Spot #3 Southern Lofoten Islands </strong></p>



<p><strong>Day 10</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-105" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-765-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">While normally a parade only for children, the Lofoten Islands Constitution Day parade is open to all!</figcaption></figure>



<p><em>Constitution Day &#8211; most everything is closed to celebrate</em></p>



<p>Pick up breakfast and a few groceries at the Circle K&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stop by the <a href="https://www.lofotoddennp.com/en/visitor-center/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.lofotoddennp.com/en/visitor-center/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lofoten Store</a> for souvenirs and information (specifically for Constitution Day)</p>



<p>Walk in the Constitution Day parade (from Moskenes to Sørvågen)</p>



<p>(This was kinda specific to our trip, feel free to take this time to go for a drive, hike, or on a fun tour. Some ideas to get you going &#8211; <a href="https://sagaadventureslofoten.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sagaadventureslofoten.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sea kayak in Reine Bay</a>, drive the E10 in either direction and check out the lovely beaches, or <a href="https://www.fjordtours.com/en/norway/things-to-do/fjord-cruise/rib-boat-tours/lofoten-trollfjord-sea-eagle-safari" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.fjordtours.com/en/norway/things-to-do/fjord-cruise/rib-boat-tours/lofoten-trollfjord-sea-eagle-safari">take a tour to see Sea Eagles</a>!)</p>



<p>Get lunch at Tapperiet Bistro (fish and chips and fish of the day were both EXCELLENT)</p>



<p>Climb Reinebringen (about 3-4 hours) eat some hiking chocolate and enjoy the view from the top&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rest and enjoy dinner at home</p>



<p><strong>Day 11&nbsp;</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-98" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-683x1024.jpg 683w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-768x1151.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-827-scaled.jpg 1708w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">These massive racks can dry hundreds of fish at a time</figcaption></figure></div>


<p class="has-small-font-size"><em>These next two days had really bad weather. Because many of the hikes are up mountains and fairly exposed and slippery, we had to change our plans. I’ll include a list of hikes in case you have nice weather and want to get outside at the bottom of this page.)</em></p>



<p>Drive to Å and explore the cool coastline, and get a cinnamon bun at the <a href="https://www.instagram.com/bakerietia?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/bakerietia?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&amp;igsh=ZDNlZDc0MzIxNw==" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bakery</a> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f60a.png" alt="😊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<p>Take the E10 to Leknes &#8211; stopping at pretty places for photos along the way&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you are in the Lofoten Islands from late winter to late spring, you will probably see the racks of dried fish, most of which are Cod. These are super cool to walk under and get a closer look at the unique, no-salt drying method that fishers have used for hundreds of years to preserve their precious fish.</p>



<p>Lunch at the mall plus quick shopping for gifts</p>



<p>Visit the<a href="https://www.lofotr.no/en/lofotr-vikingmuseum/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.lofotr.no/en/lofotr-vikingmuseum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Lofotr Viking Museum</a> (the chieftain’s longhouse was particularly cool.)</p>



<p>Drive back, hitting up the beaches and/or side roads along the way, and really get into the spirit of exploration and adventure</p>



<p><em>If you want to get back quickly, you can do the afternoon sea kayak, we wanted to do the evening one, it gets done at 11:30 pm or so</em></p>



<p>Walk to <a href="https://sagaadventureslofoten.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sagaadventureslofoten.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saga Lofoten </a>for a 3-hour sea kayak</p>



<p><strong>Day 12</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-97" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-892-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">This fishing village shows what life was like over a century ago in the Lofoten Islands</figcaption></figure>



<p>Drive to Nusfjord and check out the historic fishing village. Be sure to visit the panoramic viewpoint and &#8211; for even more adventure &#8211; walk out to the small lighthouse at the end.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Have a late lunch (the <a href="https://nusfjordarcticresort.com/cuisine/#oriana" data-type="URL" data-id="https://nusfjordarcticresort.com/cuisine/#oriana" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pizza restaurant</a> opens at 3 and quickly gets busy. If you for sure want a spot, make a reservation, or hope you get lucky and they have room. The Pear Cider was excellent!</p>



<p>Enjoy the drive back, stopping at side roads, and seeing what cool things you can discover. If the weather is good, consider a hike!</p>



<p>Light Dinner at home&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Day 13</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-99" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Norway-975-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">&#8220;What do we say to the God of Death? Not today.&#8221; -Game of Thrones</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Wake up early and head to Ryten Trailhead (grabbing cinnamon buns at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://sakrisoy.no/seafood/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://sakrisoy.no/seafood/" target="_blank">Anita’s</a> along the way. If you feel up to it, they have excellent Stockfish, be brave and give some a try)</p>



<p>Climb the mountain! (Plan on closer to 4 hours for the direct route, and if you want to take the route to the beach, add on an extra hour or two)</p>



<p>Lofoten Hiking list:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Bunes Beach + Helvetestinden (need to take a ferry)</li>



<li>Hermannsdalstinden (hardcore)</li>



<li>or just to the Munken stop if you want to not be intense hiking all-day</li>



<li>Horseid Beach&nbsp;</li>



<li>Kvalvika Beach to Ryten Mountain&nbsp;</li>



<li>Reinebringen</li>



<li>Tindstinden</li>



<li>Håen (on the next island over, accessible by plane or ferry)</li>



<li>Veggen</li>



<li>Delp</li>
</ul>



<p>Beaches to see</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Kvalvika&nbsp;</li>



<li>Horseid</li>



<li>Bunes</li>



<li>Skagsanden</li>



<li>Hauklandstranda</li>



<li>Unstad (for surfing or surfer watching!)</li>
</ul>



<p class="has-small-font-size">*<em>Now it is time for a gentle observation. I love to travel, but it doesn&#8217;t mean every single trip has perfect choices and outcomes every time. Take what you need from this next section, knowing that this much travel all at once was exhausting. I will probably make another post on how to survive a crazy amount of flights or long-leg flights, but that is not the purpose of this particular post. A little exhaustion keeps you young, right?</em>*</p>



<p><em>Catch the flight out of Leknes to Bødo, then Bødo to Bergen. Check into the Bergen Airport Hotel and catch about 4-6 hours of sleep</em></p>



<p><strong>Day 14</strong></p>



<p>Pop on the 6:20 am flight to Frankfurt, then the 11-hour flight to San Fransisco, before taking the final flight home to Salt Lake City. Feel accomplished for taking a <span style="text-decoration: underline;">5-flight</span> adventure, then sleep for about 14 hours.</p>



<p></p>



<p> That is the whole epic adventure! If you have other questions about my trip to Norway,  please don&#8217;t hesitate to reach out! Send me a DM on my <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.instagram.com/michellecholiman/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/michellecholiman/" target="_blank">Instagram</a> or leave a comment. I have a highlight story saved to my Instagram page if you want to experience the whole amazing experience &#8211; check it out! Happy traveling! </p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/norway-adventure-itinerary/">My Complete 2-Week Itinerary from my EPIC trip to Norway</a> appeared first on <a href="/">Michelle Holiman</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
